Contact

anubhamane@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/anubhamane (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Social Entrepreneurship Mentoring Public Speaking

Languages

English (Full Professional) Hindi (Full Professional) French (Elementary)

Certifications

"Learn IT, Girl!" 3rd Edition Mentor

Honors-Awards

Amul Vidyashree Award India's Top 100 Young Leaders Award 2017

35 Under 35- Best Startup In Education

Indian Women Leadership Excellence Award 2019

Anubha Maneshwar

Forbes Asia Under 30| Founder GirlScript|Indian Women Leadership Excellence Award| Featured in Ted.com and SWE Magazine Nagpur

Summary

Anubha Maneshwar founded a non-profit company called GirlScript Foundation to help beginners in technology. Currently, her organization is working in 56 cities of India and has impacted over 40000 beginners. She has been featured in Forbes Under 30 Asia List of 2020 under the Social Entrepreneurs category and in Top 8 of Technology Playmaker Award by Booking.com at London UK. She is the winner of the Indian Women Leadership Excellence Award, 35 Under 35 Awards in Best Startup for Education Category and India's Top 100 Young Leaders Award. A mentor at Mozilla Open Leaders Program, Learn IT Girl and speaker at Tedx, PyCon North America. She loves to help people and wants to transform how the education system works in India via tech and communities.

Experience

Doozie Innovation & Incubation Center of Excellence Startup Mentor May 2020 - Present (4 months)

Helping and guiding entrepreneurs to make sure that their idea transforms into a million-dollar business. Our online incubation program is now available in 30+ countries with 50+ mentors and 100+ investors for 100+ entrepreneurs.

GirlScript Summer of Code Co-Founder February 2018 - Present (2 years 7 months) Remote

GirlScript Summer of Code is 3 month long open source contribution program. NGOs are being helped in making their tech projects for free by students across globe. The first edition saw participation of 1000 participants and 151 mentors. The main aim is to help beginners to get started in open source development.

GirlScript Foundation

Founding Executive Director February 2017 - Present (3 years 7 months)

Nagpur, Maharashtra, India

Hasura

DevRel

July 2019 - December 2019 (6 months)

Mozilla Open Leaders

Mentor

August 2017 - November 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Remote

Anubha is mentoring Janet from London for her project Crowd2MapTanzania with 3500+ online volunteers and Orlando from Mexico for his Non-Profit. Mozilla Open Leadership Cohort -5 has started from February, 2018.

Learn IT, Girl

Mentor

September 2017 - February 2018 (6 months)

Remote

Learn IT, Girl is an international initiative to support and mentor women in technology. Anubha was a mentor for Round-3.

Lean In India

Chapter Lead

November 2016 - February 2018 (1 year 4 months)

Nagpur, Maharashtra, India

An organization started by Facebook COO Sheryl Sandberg to empower women worldwide!

Django Girls

Initiator and Organisor

October 2016 - October 2017 (1 year 1 month)

Nagpur Area, India

During each of their events, 30-60 women build their first web application using HTML, CSS, Python and Django.

TECXTRA TECHNOLOGIES PTV. LTD.

Internship

August 2016 - November 2016 (4 months)

Nagpur Area, India

Developed a project on Data Transmission using wireless communication: LiFi technology using .Net and Embedded C.

Education

Kendriya Vidyalaya

High School, PCM · (2005 - 2012)

Udacity

Front End Web Developer Nanodegree Program, Web

Development · (2018 - 2018)

Nagpur University

Bachelor of Engineering (BE), Computer Engineering · (2013 - 2017)

Y Combinator

Startup School, Entrepreneurship/Entrepreneurial Studies · (2019 - 2019)